<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>torras</title>
    <link>https://pedrotorreao.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on torras</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© torras</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 19:40:14 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pedrotorreao.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Big-O Overview</title>
      <link>https://pedrotorreao.github.io/posts/big-o-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 23:51:48 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pedrotorreao.github.io/posts/big-o-overview/</guid>
      <description>Big-O: Time and Space Complexity Analisys Definition The Big-O notation provides us the information of how fast a given algorithm is. It allows us to compare the number of operations and informs us of how quickly the algorithm grows. This particular way of measuring the runtime of an algorithm takes into account the worst case, i.e. in the worst possible scenario we can be sure that an algorithm performance won&amp;rsquo;t be worse than its Big-O notation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://pedrotorreao.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 19:40:14 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pedrotorreao.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello, my name is Pedro, but you can call me torras!
I&amp;rsquo;m an electrical engineer, currently working as a Embedded Software Developer for the automotive industry. I figured out a little too late into my college time that I wanted to work specifically with software engineering, so ever since I graduated I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to learn the fundamentals and build knowledge whenever I can, so that one day I&amp;rsquo;ll hopefully be able to fully migrate areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>https://pedrotorreao.github.io/posts/misc/firstpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 18:05:48 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pedrotorreao.github.io/posts/misc/firstpost/</guid>
      <description>Hello, this is my first post, hopefully this time I got it right (not proud to admit that I struggled quite a bit)!
I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting mostly about my learnings on software engineering in general, possibly some personal opinions and the occasional rant.
Anyway, just a regular blog, if it happens to be of help to someone, awesome! Otherwise, it will entertain me (for some time).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>