<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on torras</title>
    <link>https://pedrotorreao.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on torras</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© torras</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 19:22:42 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pedrotorreao.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Object Oriented Programming (OOP)</title>
      <link>https://pedrotorreao.github.io/posts/object-oriented-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 19:22:42 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pedrotorreao.github.io/posts/object-oriented-programming/</guid>
      <description>Basics Programming paradigm which focuses on the organization of the software into reusable pieces of code called classes, based on the grouping of related data and behaviors. Theses classes are user-defined data types that can be thought of as general blueprints or recipes that define the structure for objects. Objects are concrete instances of classes. They usually have more specifically defined data and they can be used to model real-world objects and/or more abstract entities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arrays</title>
      <link>https://pedrotorreao.github.io/posts/arrays/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 22:12:26 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pedrotorreao.github.io/posts/arrays/</guid>
      <description>Array Definition Array is a fundamental data structure which consists of a collection of elements and all elements are of the same type. Array elements can be accessed directly by using its position/index keeping in mind that arrays are zero-based which means that its position count begins at 0.
Arrays are usually stored contiguously in memory, which just means that all elements are stored sequentially one after the other in memory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big-O Overview</title>
      <link>https://pedrotorreao.github.io/posts/big-o-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 23:51:48 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pedrotorreao.github.io/posts/big-o-overview/</guid>
      <description>Big-O: Time and Space Complexity Analisys Definition The Big-O notation provides us the information of how fast a given algorithm is. It allows us to compare the number of operations and informs us of how quickly the algorithm grows. This particular way of measuring the runtime of an algorithm takes into account the worst case, i.e. in the worst possible scenario we can be sure that an algorithm performance won&amp;rsquo;t be worse than its Big-O notation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>https://pedrotorreao.github.io/posts/misc/firstpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 18:05:48 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pedrotorreao.github.io/posts/misc/firstpost/</guid>
      <description>Hello, this is my first post, hopefully this time I got it right (not proud to admit that I struggled quite a bit)!
I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting mostly about my learnings on software engineering in general, possibly some personal opinions and the occasional rant.
Anyway, just a regular blog, if it happens to be of help to someone, awesome! Otherwise, it will entertain me (for some time).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>